<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dvisvgm News</title>
    <description>News about the DVI to SVG converter dvisvgm.</description>
    <link>https://dvisvgm.de/News</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 09:52:34 +0200</pubDate>
    <language>en</language>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.14 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/#4468f9499cd26017882826f25736c181</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 09:48:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>4468f9499cd26017882826f25736c181</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Added processing of SVG <code>path</code> elements inserted by &ldquo;raw&rdquo; specials in order to treat them similar to generated ones.</li>
<li>Added support for native font references lacking a file name suffix.</li>
<li>Improved the lookup of native fonts.</li>
<li>Improved the removal of redundant SVG group elements.</li>
<li>Fixed the conversion of empty glyphs to TTF/WOFF data.</li>
<li>Updated the bundled <a href="https://github.com/google/woff2">WOFF2 library</a>.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.13.4 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/#80bac74a072a749b3ebc7726a80a0ab6</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 11:49:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>80bac74a072a749b3ebc7726a80a0ab6</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fixed the size of bounding boxes applied when converting multiple pages
(<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/182">issue #182</a>).</li>
<li>Try to enable the old PDF interpreter when using Ghostscript &gt;= 9.56.0.
<em>dvisvgm</em> does not work with Ghostscript&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.ghostscript.com/blog/pdfi.html">new PDF interpreter</a>.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.13.3 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/#25fddacdd30de997cedabdd597cd8d8d</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 12:40:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>25fddacdd30de997cedabdd597cd8d8d</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Added SVG optimizer module <code>reassign-clippaths</code> that searches for duplicate <code>clipPath</code> elements, removes them, and updates the <code>clip-path</code> references.</li>
<li>Replaced the method used to clip embedded EPS/PDF graphics that now usually results in faster rendering of the affected SVG sections.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression regarding transformations of embedded EPS/PDF graphics.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.13.2 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/#0ad29b27d5fc33fc8a3dda38a8d2186f</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 14:33:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>0ad29b27d5fc33fc8a3dda38a8d2186f</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This small release improves the clipping of embedded EPS/PDF graphics
(<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/176">issue #176</a>).</p>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.13.1 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/#cac0a6dd77a51a4ac4ebe47b653b4442</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 10:06:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>cac0a6dd77a51a4ac4ebe47b653b4442</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Enabled the evaluation of expression <code>{?(...)}</code> in special <code>dvisvgm:rawdef</code>
(<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/175">issue #175</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed a regression concerning the positioning of PDF graphics with special <code>pdffile</code>
(<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/174">issue #174</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed some build issues for older C++ compilers.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.13 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/#44794f1bf7aeef1aecbf496110744161</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 12:09:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>44794f1bf7aeef1aecbf496110744161</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Added the functionality to sequentially convert multiple EPS files given on the command-line.</li>
<li>Added variables <code>n</code> and <code>N</code> to option <code>--output</code> that represent the number of the file currently being processed and the total number of input files given on the command-line, respectively.</li>
<li>Fixed the selection of the hash algorithm set by option <code>--page-hashes</code>.</li>
<li>Improved the computation of glyph heights and depths.</li>
<li>The SVG optimizer now also simplifies <code>transform</code> attributes when collapsing group elements.</li>
<li>Extended several paragraphs of the manual page with more detailed information on the corresponding topics.</li>
<li>Updated the bundled <a href="https://github.com/Cyan4973/xxHash">xxHash</a> library to version 0.8.1.</li>
<li>Updated the bundled <a href="https://github.com/google/googletest">GoogleTest</a> framework to version 1.11.0.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information on PDF support as of Ghostscript 9.56.0</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/#1dc7a72ee07bdf41b0faaa031777dbf3</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 10:11:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>1dc7a72ee07bdf41b0faaa031777dbf3</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Ghostscript has introduced a completely <a href="https://www.ghostscript.com/blog/pdfi.html">rewritten implementation of its PDF interpreter</a>,
which is now implemented in C instead of PostScript. This has a lot of advantages besides the performance improvements. For third-party
applications like <em>dvisvgm</em>, however, this change has significant impact on the functions that can be provided. <em>dvisvgm</em> relies on the
possibility to overwrite PostScript and PDF operators in order to directly communicate with the interpreter. The nice thing about the
current PostScript-based PDF interpreter is the fact that both PostScript and PDF code can be treated almost equally.</p>
<p>As of Ghostscript 9.56.0, this will no longer be possible, and as far as I can tell from the documentation, there is no way to
replicate the current functionality. As a consequence, all PDF functionality currently available in <em>dvisvgm</em> will no longer work with the
upcoming Ghostscript releases. Therefore, it will require the parallel installation of Ghostscript 9.55.0 or earlier. In the long run,
I&rsquo;ll probably have to drop PDF support since I don&rsquo;t have the resources to implement a completely new PDF handler.</p>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.12 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/#0bc5191266f5d77c936e8e667cef5f50</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 12:35:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>0bc5191266f5d77c936e8e667cef5f50</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Added transparency support for SVG elements created outside the PS handler (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/148">issue #148</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed a spacing issue caused by unexpected newline characters in SVG output.</li>
<li>Fixed PostScript errors occurred when defining (yet unsupported) shading patterns.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug that prevented proper coloring of PostScript tiling patterns (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/158">issue #158</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed graphics displacements that occurred if the PDF MediBox is not located at the origin.</li>
<li>Fixed the handling of root directories of file paths.</li>
<li>Improved the handling of drive letters (Windows only).</li>
<li>Several code refactorings and improvements.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.11.1 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/2/#e423fc038b1ff9a9ba28e1b1cfbd3d6f</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 15:20:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>e423fc038b1ff9a9ba28e1b1cfbd3d6f</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is a small maintenance release.</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed possible ambiguities of GID to charcode mappings (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/147">issue #147</a>).</li>
<li>Refactored the representation of token objects in class <code>Calculator</code>.</li>
<li>Few minor code and test improvements.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.11 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/2/#45089adf53a690978eb4e8d47ffd190e</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 11:28:08 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>45089adf53a690978eb4e8d47ffd190e</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Added fallback mechanism for JFM-based virtual fonts as proposed by Takuji Tanaka (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/144">issue #144</a>).</li>
<li>Improved detection of proper CMap files for currently selected font encoding.</li>
<li>Fixed processing of Unicode surrogates present in CMap files.</li>
<li>Fixed handling of <code>pdf:mapline</code> and <code>pdf:mapfile</code> specials.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.10.1 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/2/#9f68ebd62bc0a3cf963a572fe77e0bd2</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 11:13:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>9f68ebd62bc0a3cf963a572fe77e0bd2</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is a small maintenance release.</p>
<ul>
<li>Added support for the new <a href="https://www.ghostscript.com/doc/current/Language.htm#Transparency">Ghostscript transparency operators</a>
<code>.setfillconstantalpha</code> and <code>.setstrokeconstantalpha</code>.</li>
<li>Added support for the new Ghostscript versioning scheme introduced with GS 9.53.0.</li>
<li>Added few additional information to the <a href="/Manpage/">manual page</a>.</li>
<li>Updated the bundled <a href="https://github.com/google/brotli">Brotli library</a> to version 1.0.9.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.10 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/2/#2df05e60a6483e32a6c2ab7e1bb3a697</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 10:23:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>2df05e60a6483e32a6c2ab7e1bb3a697</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is a maintenance release with the following additions and changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Added evaluation of <a href="http://www.luatex.org">Lua<span class="tex">T<sub>E</sub>X</span></a> native font definitions.</li>
<li>Added computation of of italic correction for fake slanted glyphs.</li>
<li><em>dvisvgm</em> now creates dedicated temporary folders for each call of the program to prevent file collisions between different processes.</li>
<li>Added evaluation of internal <a href="https://www.ghostscript.com">Ghostscript</a> operators <code>.fillstroke</code> and <code>.eofillstroke</code> introduced
with GS 9.52 to implement PDF operators <code>B</code> and <code>B*</code> (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/139">issue #139</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed and improved optimization of nested group elements.</li>
<li>Fixed optimization of <code>scale</code> transformation.</li>
<li>Fixed optimization of <code>transform</code> attributes applied to images and clipping paths.</li>
<li>Fixed processing of PostScript operator <code>eoclip</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed processing of clipping path intersections that involve different fill rules.</li>
<li>Fixed processing of <code>{?(...)}</code> expressions (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/136">issue #136</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed error message about unmatched closing tags in XML parser.</li>
<li>Updated bundled <a href="https://www.freetype.org">FreeType</a> library to version 2.10.2.</li>
<li>Updated bundled <a href="https://www.xxhash.com">xxHash</a> library to version 0.8.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.9.1 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/2/#7d856da14b815b8a8abea3cdae767d76</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 13:16:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>7d856da14b815b8a8abea3cdae767d76</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is a small maintenance release with the following changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Added macro <code>{?(expr)}</code> to enable the evaluation of math expressions in raw SVG fragments
(<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/130">issue #130</a>).</li>
<li>Multiplication operator <code>*</code> preceding an opening parentheses can now be omitted in math expressions.</li>
<li>Fixed the evaluation of transformation command <code>scale(c)</code> which is now correctly treated as <code>scale(c,c)</code>
(<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/131">issue #131</a>).</li>
<li>Minor layout optimizations of the <a href="/Manpage/dvisvgm.pdf">PDF version of the manual page</a>.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.9 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/2/#5651dc6a7c24b18f3867668516712587</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 13:18:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>5651dc6a7c24b18f3867668516712587</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The main new feature of this release is the conversion of bitmap images present in PostScript and PDF data.
All bitmaps are embedded into the generated SVG files encoded as Base64 strings. The default format used
for this is JPEG because it allows for high compression rates and therefore moderate impact on the SVG file size.
If you prefer a lossless format, you can switch to one of the supported PNG variants by using the new command-line
option <a href="/Manpage/#opt-bitmap-format"><code>--bitmap-format</code></a>. Further information about the available
formats and the usage of this option can be found on the manual page.</p>
<p><strong>Summary of additions and fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added the processing of PostScript operators <code>image</code> and <code>colorimage</code> which now allows <em>dvisvgm</em>
to embed bitmap images present in PS/PDF files into the generated SVG files.</li>
<li>Added command-line option <a href="/Manpage/#opt-bitmap-format"><code>--bitmap-format</code></a> to set
the format used to embed bitmaps present in EPS/PDF files.</li>
<li>Added a fallback method to retrieve the resolution of GF files if <code>stdout</code> of the Metafont subprocess can&rsquo;t
be read through a pipe for some reason (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/129">issue #129</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed the broken conversion of PostScript tiling patterns.</li>
<li>Fixed the functionality of PostScript operators <code>xshow</code>, <code>yshow</code>, and <code>xyshow</code> for multibyte characters.</li>
<li>Fixed a PostScript error that was triggered by yet unsupported shading types &lt; 4.</li>
<li>Prevent negative <code>height</code> and <code>width</code> attributes created by <a href="/Manpage/#opt-optimize">optimizer module</a>
<code>simplify-transform</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential segfault caused by deep recursion in huge SVG trees.</li>
<li>Look for Ghostscript library name <code>libgs.dylib.N</code> additionally to <code>libgs.N.dylib</code> (Mac only).</li>
<li>Ensure that <code>make install</code> installs the bundled manual page if it can&rsquo;t be rebuilt due to missing build tools.</li>
<li>Updated the bundled <a href="https://www.xxhash.com">xxHash</a> library to version 0.7.3.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.8.2 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/2/#d2a122bf30fb68ee24d061cc34560ae0</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 11:58:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>d2a122bf30fb68ee24d061cc34560ae0</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is a small maintenance release with the following changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>If available, <em>dvisvgm</em> now calls <code>mf-nowin</code> instead of <code>mf</code> to process Metafont files (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/121">issue #121</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed the switching between PostScript&rsquo;s null device and the regular page device in PS operator <code>restore</code> (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/122">issue #122</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed a PostScript error triggered by backslashes in file paths (Windows only, <a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/123">issue #123</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed a build issue related to GCC on Solaris 11.</li>
<li>Some code cleanup.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.8.1 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/2/#8d0ef4dc302ef6102e094359ddf31b2d</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 16:25:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>8d0ef4dc302ef6102e094359ddf31b2d</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Added SVG optimizer module <code>simplify-text</code> to move common attributes from <code>tspan</code> elements to the enclosing <code>text</code> element. Redundant <code>tspan</code> elements are removed afterwards.</li>
<li>Added support for PS operator <code>nulldevice</code> which is used by a couple of LaTeX packages.
It&rsquo;s used to temporarily suppress graphic output when executing drawing or text commands.</li>
<li>Absolute paths given in special <code>psfile</code> are now retained in the SVG file when referencing external image files.</li>
<li>Some code refactorings.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.8 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/3/#57192fe118cc7abbba232e51f3d2adf0</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 17:42:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>57192fe118cc7abbba232e51f3d2adf0</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is a small feature release with the following additions/changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Added support for JPEG, PNG, PDF, and SVG files to special <code>psfile</code>.</li>
<li>Added support for Ghostscript 9.50 which introduced incompatible changes regarding option <code>-dSAFER</code>. Due
to security reasons <code>SAFER</code> is now <a href="https://www.ghostscript.com/doc/9.50/Use.htm#Safer">active by default</a>
and therefore conflicts with <code>DELAYBIND</code> and <code>WRITESYSTEMDICT</code>. Since <em>dvisvgm</em> requires the latter two to work
correctly, Ghostscript must now be called with <code>-dDELAYSAFER</code>. Otherwise, it prints some warning messages and
stops with a PostScript error, e.g. like so:
<span class="d-inline-flex">
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-text" data-lang="text">*** WARNING - you have selected SAFER, indicating you want Ghostscript
              to execute in a safer environment, but at the same time
              have selected DELAYBIND. Unless you use this option with
              care (and specifically, remember to call .bindnow) it is
              possible that malicious code may be able to evade the
              limited security offered by the SAFER option.

*** WARNING - you have selected SAFER, indicating you want Ghostscript
              to execute in a safer environment, but at the same time
              have selected WRITESYSTEMDICT. Unless you use this option with
              care and specifically, remember to execute code like:
                     &#34;systemdict readonly pop&#34;
 PostScript error: invalidfileaccess in run</code></pre></div>
</span><br/>
<em>dvisvgm</em> 2.8 fixes this issue. All versions prior to 2.8 don&rsquo;t work together with GS 9.50 (and later).</li>
<li>Added support for <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/SVG11/paths.html#PathDataEllipticalArcCommands">elliptical arc segments</a> in graphics paths.</li>
<li>Added support for CMap operator <code>begincidchar</code> (thanks to Akira Kakuto for sending the patch).</li>
<li>Added suport for experimental 128-bit <a href="https://github.com/Cyan4973/xxHash#new-experimental-hash-algorithm"><code>XXH3</code> hashes</a>.</li>
<li>The SVG optimizer module <code>simplify-transform</code> has been extended to incorporate translation and scaling components
into positional and size attributes if possible.</li>
<li>The CRC32 checksums used to verify the sanity of cache files has been replaced with <code>XXH32</code> hashes.</li>
<li>The bundled <a href="http://potrace.sourceforge.net">potrace</a> library has been updated to version 1.16.</li>
<li>The bundled <a href="http://www.xxhash.com">xxHash</a> library has been updated to version 0.7.2.</li>
<li>The bundled <a href="https://github.com/google/googletest">Google Test</a> library has been updated to version 1.10.</li>
<li>Lots of code has been refactored and improved.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.7.4 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/3/#8e82b41fbfdfcdf712fa21fc5e505117</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 12:08:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>8e82b41fbfdfcdf712fa21fc5e505117</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is another small maintenance release with the following changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a memory issue occurred when calling Metafont.</li>
<li>Fixed potential rounding issues in conversion of color values (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/116">issue #116</a>).</li>
<li>Changed the location of the cache files from <code>~/.dvisvgm/cache</code> to <code>$XDG_CACHE_HOME/dvisvgm</code>
which usually expands to <code>~/.cache/dvisvgm</code> (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/112">issue #112</a>).</li>
<li>Some minor refactorings.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.7.3 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/3/#6f8e194693ecc2a26ed8c5de5adc7c8f</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 11:30:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>6f8e194693ecc2a26ed8c5de5adc7c8f</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is a small maintenance release with the following changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed randomly missing glyph paths referenced by <code>use</code> elements (<a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/dvisvgm/issues/110">issue #110</a>).</li>
<li>Minor updates of the <a href="/Manpage/">manual page</a>.</li>
<li>Some code refactorings.</li>
</ul>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvisvgm 2.7.2 has been released</title>
      <link>https://mgieseki.github.io/dvisvgm/News/page/3/#6c01c957e0db5e41406e40486fe0acd1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 11:01:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>6c01c957e0db5e41406e40486fe0acd1</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This maintenance release fixes an issue introduced with Ghostscript 9.27.
The removal of the PostScript dictionaries <code>GS_PDF_ProcSet</code> and <code>pdfdict</code> from
the public interface leads to an error message when processing PDF files with
<em>dvisvgm</em>.</p>
<p>The changes in Ghostscript 9.27 also break the PDF functionality of
<a href="http://www.ghostgum.com.au/software/gsview.htm">GSview 5.0</a> by Russell Lang.
An unofficial, fixed version can be downloaded <a href="https://github.com/mgieseki/gsview/releases">here</a>.</p>
]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
